1206 E Lemon St. Tempe, AZ 85281 408.768.5896 aansari2.github.io/Adil-Ansari/ linkedin.com/in/adilcomp/ aansari2@asu.edu

#### SUMMARY

A highly motivated mechanical engineering graduate with a robust interest in STEM who has worked under independent and team working scenarios encompassing multidisciplinary fields. Values problem solving with given constraints and gives importance to communication and interpersonal skills.

# **EDUCATION**

# Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

M.Sc., Mechanical Engineering, May 2019

GPA: 3.73

Thesis: A Collation and Analysis of Two-Dimensional Unsplit Conservative Advection Methods for Volume of Fluid at Interfaces

D.C. Markarian Francisco (Communicational Markarian) Marco

B.Sc., Mechanical Engineering (Computational Mechanics), May 2016 GPA: 3.40

# WORK EXPERIENCE

## Teaching Assistant

SEMTE  $\parallel$  ASU

January 2018 - May 2019

Tempe, Arizona

Operated wind tunnel labs with sensitive equipment for Aerodynamics Lab with Lab-View. Did programming tutorials. Evaluated reports and assignments.

# Summer Technology Assistant

Saudi Aramco Schools

2013 - 2016

Ras Tanura, Saudi Arabia

Statistically analyzed middle school fitness data using algorithms under Macro-Enabled MS Office spreadsheets and documents to generate individual reports after data entry.

## **PROJECTS**

# 2019: Microjet Simulation (BioXFEL, National Science Foundation)

Working on ascertaining the dimension of micro-jets via C++ based openFOAM CFD simulations of a microjet injector designed for finding structure and function of proteins.

#### 2015-2016: Senior Capstone Project

Automated fire extinguishing mechanisms for automobiles in emergency scenarios. Lead team through planning, designing, fabrication, assembly, and testing. Minimized false positives with  $CO_2$  and IR flame sensing on embedded software.

### 2017: Multiphase Simulation Project

Generated codes for validation of state-of-the-art liquid-gas interface tracking methods.

## 2018: Spectral Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) Project

Coded a highly accurate method for modeling laminar flows and thermal heat exchange.

## 2013-2016: Engineering Projects in Community Service (EPICS)

Team Position: Deputy Leader. Partnered with STARS (Scottsdale Training & Rehabilitation Services) to engineer an efficient and reliable navigation system for **assisting visually impaired individuals**.

## 2017: Robot Trajectory Planning Project

Coded a trajectory for KUKA mechatronic robotic arms with obstacle avoidance.

# 2017: Finite Element Project

Coded a mesh and FEA solver to analyse static deformation.

# SKILLS

Main: Robotics, Mechatronics, Kinematics, Dynamics, material properties, and structural, dynamic, and thermal analysis, engineering analysis, prototyping, CAD, engineering drawings.

Numerical: Image Processing, Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD), Spectral Analysis, Trajectory Planning for Robotic Arms, Structural Finite Element Analysis (FEA) with stress, strain, deformation, modal response.

Programming Languages: MATLAB, C, Python, FORTRAN, JAVA, HTML, JavaScript, LATEX, Visual Basic.

**General**: Artificial Intelligence, Parallel/Distributed Computing, Experimental Statistics, CAD, FMEA, BOMs, QFD, Assembly, Real-time-Data Visualizations, GD&T, UNIX shell scripting, OOP, Embedded Software.

**Applications**: SOLIDWORKS, PTC CREO, MATLAB, **ANSYS Fluent**, ANSYS DesignModeler& Structural, **Microsoft Office Suite** (Macro-Enabled), Blender 3D, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe AfterEffects.

**Hardware**: Power Tools, Arduino Devices (Intel Galileo), Raspberry Pi, Oscilloscope, Micro-controllers, Linear Actuators, Short Range Binary Wireless Communication

Certifications: Fundamentals of Engineering, ASU information security training

